ประทานวิปรัฐบาลค
The government whip
ุณกรวีปริศนานันทกุณก็ออกมาสื่อสารก
Kornkawin Prasitnantakun also communicated
ับนักขาวด้วยบอกว่าเดี๋ยวว
with reporters, saying that soon
ิปจะมีการประชุมประจำสัปดาห์ม
there will be a weekly meeting
ีเรื่องของร่างกฎหมายนิรธศกรรมซึ่งท
regarding the amnesty bill, which
างวุธเขาส่งกลับมาแล้วนะครับแล้วท
Wut has sent back, and
ี่ประชุมจะได้หารือกับพักรวมรัฐบาล
the meeting will discuss with coalition parties
สิ่งที่ส.ว.อ.แก่ไขzมาว่า
what the senators amended,
เออยังไงต่อมีความเห็นกันอย่ằngไร
what to do next, what their opinions are,
แต่ในตัวส.ส.กราวีที่ดูจากประเด็นที่ถูกแก่ไขz
but looking at the amendments made
โดยส.ว.yittntอยู่ในแนวทางที่
by the senators, they are in line with
ความต้องตั้งมาทิการร่วม
the joint committee's requirements,
ของ2ส.พ.ก็ไม่ขัดครองจัดได้
which the two houses do not oppose.
ส่วนแฮะฝ่ายค้าชัดเจไม
As for the opposition, they clearly
่รับเพลงหกันทีการเท่าครับ
do not accept it at all.
ผมก็เดาว่าน่าจะเป็นเงื่อนไขมาตรา112นี่แหละ
I guess it's probably the condition of Article 112.
แล้วถ้าตั้งกันมาที่การร
And if they set up a joint
่วมก็ต้องเข้าสภาในสมัยประชุมหน้าก็อาจจะต้องช
committee, it must go to parliament in the next session, which might be
้าไปอีกหน่อยสัก2-3เดือนนะครับ
delayed another 2-3 months.
ค่ะแน่นอนถึงแม้ล่าช้าออกไป
Yes, certainly, even though it's delayed.
แต่การพิจารณาก็ยังเดินหน้าอยู่นะคะท
But the consideration is still moving forward.
างด้านของคุณสุดทินครั้งแสงสอๆ
On the side of Khun Soodtin, with a slight smile,
บัญชีรายชื่อพักเพ
the party-list candidate
ื่อไทยก็ใบสามาชิคก็ให้สัมพาดบอกว่าเร
for Thai, the member gave an interview saying that this
ื่องนี้ก็ต้องไปฟังวิฟรัฐบาทค
matter must be heard from the government
่าว่าเขาจะพิจรนากันยังไง
on how they will deliberate.
แล้วว่าตัวแทนต่าละพักก็มีความค
And since representatives from different parties have
ิดเห็นที่แตกต่างกันก็ต้องให้สมาชิคเลยมาพ
differing opinions, members must come and
ูดคุยกันนะคะซึ่งต
discuss it.
ัวของคุณสุดทิ้นมองวาเรื่องนี้สุดท้ายก
Khun Soodtin views that this matter, in the end,
็น่าจะได้ขอดสรุปแหละแล
should be concluded,
้วก็สามารถผลักดันกฎหมายฉบับนี้ออกมา
and then this bill can be successfully pushed through
ได้สำเร็จเนื่องจากว่าคนท
because those who
ี่ได้รับประโยชน์มีทั้งกลุ่มที่ผิดพลาท
will benefit include groups that have made mistakes
ความผิดเพราะกฎหมายนี้ออกมา
due to this law. Once it's passed,
แล้วก็จะเป็นการเปิดโอกาส
it will open an opportunity
ให้คนเหล่านี้ได้กลับมาใช้ชีวิตส
for these people to return to living their lives,
ร้างความปลองดองสร้างความสามารถคี
creating harmony and capability
ให้เกิดขึ้นภายในชาติ
within the nation.
พวกเขาก็จะได้ใช้สักยภาพในการพัฒนาประเทศต่อไป
They will then be able to use their potential to further develop the country.
อีกด้วยค่ะ
as well.